These Foreign-only subtitles ver. 2024-10 were created by ZoowlCZ.
[Sindarin] ♫ Ú i vethed... ♫
[English] ♫ Not the end... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ ...nâ i onnad. ♫
[English] ♫ ...it is the beginning. ♫
[Sindarin] Minlû pedich nin...
[English] Once you told me...
[Sindarin] ...i aur hen telitha.
[English] ...this day will-come.
[Sindarin] Ú i vethed... nâ i onnad.
[English] Not the end... it is the beginning.
[Sindarin] Boe bedich go Frodo.
[English] It is necessary you go with Frodo.
[Sindarin] Han bâd lîn.
It is your path.
[Sindarin] Dolen i vâd o nin.
[English] Hidden the path is from me.
[Sindarin] Si peliannen i vâd na dail lîn.
[English] The way is already spread before your feet.
[Sindarin] Si boe ú-dhannathach.
[English] Now it-is-necessary you-don’t-fall.
[Sindarin] Ae ú-esteliach nad...
[English] If you trust not things...
[Sindarin] ...estelio han...
[English] ...trust this...
[Sindarin] ...estelio ammen.
[English] ...trust us.
[Sindarin] ♫ Estelio han. ♫
[English] ♫ Trust this. ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ Estelio veleth. ♫
[English] ♫ Trust love. ♫
[Sindarin] Nach gwannatha sin?
[English] Are you going to leave in such way?
[Sindarin] Ma nathach hi gwannathach or minuial archened?
[English] You would depart after the stars fade - unseen?
[Sindarin] Ú-ethelithon.
[English] I will not return.
[Sindarin] Estelio guru lîn ne dagor.
[English] Trust in your skill in battle.
[Sindarin] Ethelithach.
[English] You will return.
[Sindarin]  Ú-bedin o gurth ne dagor.
[English] I don’t speak about death in battle.
[Sindarin] O man pedich?
[English] About what you speak?
[Sindarin] Edra le men, men na guil edwen...
[English] A path is opened for you, a path to another life...
[Sindarin] haer o auth a nîr a naeth.
[English] ...far from war and weeping and woe.
[Sindarin] Tollen, i lû.
[English] Come, it is time.
[Sindarin] I chair gwannar na Valannor. Si bado, no círar.
[English] The ships depart to Valinor. Now go, before they sail.
[Sindarin] Ah im, ú-’erin veleth lîn?
[English] And I, I-have-not love your?
[Sindarin] Gerich veleth nîn, ada.
[English] You-have my love, father.
[Sindarin] I amar prestar aen.
[English] The world is changed.
[Sindarin] Han mathon ne nen.
[English] I feel it in the water.
[Sindarin] Han mathon ne chae.
[English] I feel it in the earth.
[Sindarin] A han noston ned ’wilith.
[English] I smell it in the air.
[Sindarin] Mae carnen, Brego, mellon nîn.
[English] Well done, Brego, my friend.
[Sindarin] Le abdollen.
[English] You’re late.
[Sindarin] Hannon le.
[English] Thank you.
[Sindarin] Boe a hyn...
[English] And they should be...
[Sindarin] Neled herain... dan caer menig.
[English] Three hundred... against ten thousand.
[Sindarin] Si, beriathar hyn ammaeg na ned Edoras.
[English] Here they-will-defend them-selves sharper than at Edoras.
[Sindarin] Aragorn, nedin dagor hen ú-’erir ortheri.
[English] Aragorn, in this battle they can not win.
[Sindarin] Natha daged dhaer
[English] It will be great slaying.
[Sindarin] Ú-moe edaved, Legolas
[English] There is nothing to forgive, Legolas.
[Sindarin] Mae govannen, Haldir.
[English] Well-met, Haldir.
[Sindarin] A Eruchîn, ú-dano i faelas a hyn...
[English] O Children-of-Eru, don’t show mercy to them...
[Sindarin] ...an uben tanatha le faelas!
[English] ...for nobody will show you mercy!
[Sindarin] Dartho!
[English] Hold!
[Sindarin] Tangado a chadad!
[English] Prepare to fire!
[Sindarin] Faeg i-varv dîn na lanc...
[English] Their armour is poor below the neck...
[Sindarin] ...a nu ranc!
[English] ...and under arm!
[Sindarin] Hado i philinn!
[English] Release the arrows!
[Sindarin] Pendraith!
[English] Ladders!
[Sindarin] Na fennas!
[English] To gateway!
[Sindarin] Hado ribed! Hado!
[English] Hurl to flow! Hurl!
[Sindarin] Togo hon dad, Legolas!
[English] Bring him down, Legolas!
[Sindarin] Dago hon!
[English] Kill him!
[Sindarin] Hado i philinn!
[English] Release the arrows!
[Sindarin] Herio!
[English] Charge!
[Sindarin] Nan barad!
[English] To tower!
[Rohirric] Forð Eorlingas!
[English] Forth Eorlingas!